

- +234 807 0718 502

I am a software engineer with 2+ years of experience in both backend and frontend software design using Python, NodeJS, Javascript, CSS, HTML, and other related technologies.

As a frontend and backend software engineer, I know the workings of the web and can, with this knowledge, create intuitive UIs backed with remarkable user experiences. I'm also able to develop backend servers for both web, mobile, and desktop applications that all communicate with each other through powerful APIs built on the RESTful API development architecture.

SKILLS

ABOUT & OBJECTIVES

Frontend Development Backend Engineering API Development Frontend and Backend **Optimization**

Database Management Plugins and Extensions

Development

CERTIFICATIONS

API Engineer Travella

February 2021

Web Developer September 2018 FreeCodeCamp

LANGUAGES

English

Yoruba Very Fluent Conversational

REFERENCES

Moses Adebayo CEO at Travella +234 811 834 1190

HOBBIES

Programing and Development

Web Surfing

Gaming

Studying

Movies and Series

Outings

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer

Travella, NG

(February 2021 - March 2021)

- Oversaw the design and development of the API that was needed to develop the Travella mobile app.
- Handled the hosting and management of the PostgreSQL database connected with the Travella server.
- Conjured my frontend skills to make contributions in terms of UI and UX.

Veehue Labs, NG Lead Software Developer

(August 2020 - March 2021)

- Established Veehue Labs as a software engineering startup geared towards building software solutions for others.
- Managed up to 3 development projects at a given time while under pressure
- Recommended and consulted with clients on the most appropriate software design for their business.
- Oversaw the development team and delegated projects to other developers on the team.

Fiverr, Tel Aviv

(November 2017 - December 2020)

E-commerce Developer

- Handled the creation of e-commerce stores for businesses using platforms like Shopify and WordPress.
- Managed different projects at a time without compromising on the perfection of any.
- Made custom changes by modifying the source code of both Shopify and WordPress to suit clients' requirements.
- Ensured that each business stands out great by creating a store design that rhymes with each business' identity.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Technology Akure, NG

(November 2017 - September 2023)

4.57

Masters Physics

Currently studying applied physics in the area of energy and electronics. With more focus on combining software with hardware to solve energyrelated solutions.

Success For All High School, NG

(September 2013 - April 2016) 7Bs, 2Cs

O'Level Science

Completed every necessary requirement for the O'level degree certificate in accordance with WAEC's (West African Examination Council) requirements. Studied courses included Mathematics, English, Physics, Chemistry, Further Mathematics...